Hanekawa mentioned that you were living in a luxurious house, Senjougahara...
My mom got immersed in a cult.
All the valuables in our house were given to them.
She also incurred a huge debt.
Therefore, my parents voluntarily divorced toward the end of last year.
My father has custody of me, and we have both lived here since then.
Are you going to help me?
I won't help you. I will, however, lend you my powers.
Oh, and please make a trip home.
When you get there, I ask that you cleanse your body with holy water and change into a set of pure clothes.
Does meeting me back here around midnight sound all right?
I can do that, but...
And the reward?
Huh?
Don't play dumb.
You're not saying you'll help me for free, are you?
Well... if it makes you feel better, I guess I can charge you.
How does 100,000 yen sound?
100,000 yen.
You treat her extremely differently from how you treated me.
Really?
As I recall, the price I quoted for the class representative was also 100,000 yen.
You asked me for a whopping 5,000,000 yen!
But that was a vampire, you know. It couldn't be helped.
Don't blame anything and everything on the vampire!
Can you pay?
Of course.
No matter what I might have to do.
100,000 yen, huh?
I've finished taking a shower.
Could you get out of the way?
I can't get to my clothes.
Clothes! Put on your clothes!
That's exactly what I'm doing.
I'm saying that you should have put something on before you stepped out!
I forgot to carry them in with me.
Then at least cover yourself with a towel or something!
I don't want to do something that a poor person would do!
The first time that I've seen a girl completely nude...
Pure clothes, huh?
Do you think he'd prefer white clothing?
I don't know.
I don't have any bras or panties that don't have patterns.
I don't care!
Araragi-kun,
You haven't gotten aroused from seeing me nude, have you?
Even if I have, it wouldn't be my fault!
Done. You can turn around.
I see. Seriously...
What's your motive?!
What?
This is a special service as a reward for today.
You should at least be happy.
Be a little bit happy, will you?
I should be getting mad.
You should at least give me a critique as a courtesy.
A critique...?
Y-You have a nice figure... How's that?
Terrible.
It's exactly why you will forever be a virgin.
Forever?!
Did you come from the future?!
Please refrain from spitting.
I'll be infected by your virginity.
Like a man's virginity could spread to a woman!
Hold up... Come to think of it...
The topic is proceeding on the assumption that I am a virgin.
It's true that my words are biased.
I'm glad you realize that.
Just don't spit.
Your amateurish virginity will infect me.
I admit it.
I am a virgin!
Don't worry.
I'll keep this a secret from Hanekawa-san.
Why her?
Isn't she the girl you have a crush on?
You guys talk frequently, don't you?
That's incorrect.
That's just because Hanekawa is honestly the type that looks after others.
"The most useless people are pitiful."
"They will definitely be used."
She always has such amusing misconceptions.
That sure is an amusing misconception, isn't it?
Even though the most useless people are just the most foolish.
No, I didn't say that much.
It was written all over your face.
No it wasn't.
Having predicted that you'd say that, I already wrote it on your face.
No way in hell are you that well prepared!
Hanekawa-san was also helped by Oshino-san before as well, right?
You could say that, I guess.
That's why I think he's more or less trustworthy.
It's not just my testimony.
Hanekawa says so, too.
I see.
However, Araragi-kun...
If I could believe him that easily, I would have been tricked countless times.
That's why I can never have such optimistic thoughts.
You took the time to put it on; why remove it?
I forgot to dry my hair.
You... Could it be that you're just an idiot?
Please don't speak such rude words.
You could hurt my feelings.
You mentioned optimism just now, right?
Isn't that how it goes?
Maybe.
But being optimistic isn't a bad thing, is it?
It's not like you're doing anything bad.
It's also not like you're cheating either.
Not doing anything bad, huh?
Isn't that so?
That's true.
But...
It may be considered a form of cheating.
Huh?
Nothing.
Say, Araragi-kun.
May I ask you something?
What did you mean when you said it's comparable to the pattern on the moon?
Huh? What are you talking about?
Didn't you say that to Oshino-san back then?
Oh, that?
It is said that when you see the moon in Japan, its patterns resemble rabbits pounding rice cakes.
Whereas abroad, a crab or a beautiful woman can be seen.
Oh, is that so?
I'm surprised you know such useless things.
This is the first time since birth that I've admired you.
It's nothing.
I'm just familiar with astronomy and cosmology.
It's fine.
There's no need to act cool in front of me.
Besides, you don't know about anything else, do you?
Are you aware of what verbal abuse is?
You should tell that to the police officer in charge of verbal abuse.
Why, you...
You only want to show me that proud body of yours.
Proud body of mine?
I'm not that arrogant.
I'm just not used to wearing clothes.
They're heavy.
But I didn't think you would be so knowledgeable, Araragi-kun.
I'm surprised.
It might actually be possible that there is a brain inside your head.
That's obvious.
Obvious?
A creature like you having a brain residing in his skull...
...is already a miracle in and of itself.
You... think I am really stupid, don't you?
How did you know?
You're actually expressing genuine shock!
Because of my carelessness, Araragi-kun realized that his brain is slower than others'.
I feel so guilty.
Hey, wait a minute.
Is my stupidity level really that grave?
My standardized test score is seventy-four.
Mine's forty-six...
When rounded, it becomes zero.
Huh?
Liar. Forty-six would round up to...
Hey, you rounded from the tens place!
How could you do that to my standardized test score?
One hundred.
I can't grasp the sense of victory without expanding the difference.
You also rounded your own score from the tens place...
I've decided.
If everything goes well, let's visit Hokkaido to eat crab.
Well, I guess that would be fine...
You will be going as well.
Why?
Ah, don't you know?
Crab is very delicious.
Oshino-san, you were a priest?
No, I'm not.
Even though it was my specialization in university, I have not been employed by any shrine.
I thought over a lot of things.
You look like you've been purified nicely, miss.
It is quite well done.
Just to confirm, are you wearing make-up?
I thought it best not to, hence I did not put any on.
Right.
Your judgment is correct.
Has Araragi-kun taken a shower?
Yeah, I took a shower at Senjougahara's place.
No problem.
You still haven't improved, have you?
Don't say such unnecessary things.
By the way, Oshino...
Is this crab or whatever easy to exorcise?
Your way of thinking is really violent, Araragi-kun.
Did anything good happen?
Shinobu-chan and that nymphomaniac cat attacked you and that class representative out of malice...
But that's not the case with the crab.
What do you mean?
Didn't I say that the opponent is a god?
As such, we are not going to exorcise it.
Starting now, we are going to pray.
Your attitudes must be respectful.
Is it something that can be returned if prayed for?
Senjougahara's...
weight.
Body mass.
Maybe?
They are not so stubborn as to reject desperate wishes from humans.
Though, gods are a bunch of careless beings.
Careless, as in?
They don't care about the personal problems of humans.
In fact, gods can't even differentiate between the age, gender, or weight of the three of us.
Hey, is that crab still beside me?
Yeah, it's still right beside you.
But it's also everywhere.
If you want to summon it, you need to follow step-by-step procedures.
Both of you, look down at the floor.
Keep your heads down.
Huh?
This place is already right in front of the god.
What's this?
Drinking sake seems to be able to shorten the distance to gods.
I'm underage.
It's not like you're drinking till you drop. Just take a sip.
Okay, you two.
Let's start by relaxing.
This position belongs to you.
You're standing in your rightful position.
Yes.
Close your eyes while continuing to tilt your head.
Begin counting.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine...
Have you calmed down?
Yes.
All right, then answer my questions.
Miss, what is your name?
Senjougahara Hitagi.
What is the name of the school that you're attending?
Naoetsu Private High School.
When is your birthday?
July 7th.
Who is your favorite novelist?
Yumeno Kyuusaku.
Could you tell us about an experience of failure you had as a child?
I don't want to reveal that.
What is your favorite classical music?
I'm not very interested in music.
How did you feel when you graduated from elementary school?
I took it as nothing more than a transfer to middle school.
I simply moved from one public school to another.
What type of person was your first love?
I don't want to reveal that.
Up till now, what has been your most painful memory?
What's wrong?
Your most painful memory...
What I'm asking is that you recall your worst memory.
M-My mother...
Your mother?
She got immersed in a cult.
Is that all?
What do you mean "is that all?"
Continue.
What happened?
A-A high-ranking cult member came to my house.
My mom brought him there.
Brought him there... What happened next?
He claimed that it was a ritual...
I...
...was violated.
He... attempted to rape me.
I see.
You said that he attempted to rape you, meaning it didn't happen?
I used a spiked shoe beside me to hit him.
But... my mom did not come to my rescue.
After that?
Because I injured the high-ranking cult member, my mom was...
Your mom was punished, correct?
Yes.
But I always find myself thinking about it.
If I hadn't resisted at that time, maybe my mother wouldn't have fallen into such a pathetic state.
Then our relationship would not have been broken.
Then, miss, those are your feelings.
No matter how heavy they are, they are things you must carry with you.
You can't push them onto someone else.
Pushing them onto someone else...
Without looking away...
Open your eyes and take a look.
Can you see anything?
I see it.
It's the same as that time.
The same as that time.
A huge crab.
I can see a crab.
Is that so?
I can't see anything.
What about you Araragi-kun?
But I see it very clearly.
Is that so? Then...
Then... isn't there something you need to say?
Something I need to say?
Senjougahara!
All right, fine.
Seriously, what an impatient god.
It's an energetic fellow, I must say.
Did something good happen?
Hey, Oshino!
I got it.
Change of plans.
I have to do this now.
Take that!
In the end, this is still a question of self-reflection.
If praying does not work, and words are ineffective...
...what's left is to fight.
But...
Regardless, if it's disposed of like that...
...according to procedure, this problem will be solved.
For this case, I say that's one possible solution.
A possible solution?
I generally hate crabs...
...because they're hard to eat.
Wait.
Please wait, Oshino-san.
Wait?
Wait for what, miss?
Just now, I was merely frightened.
I will do this properly.
I can do it myself.
Then help yourself.
Give it a try.
I'm sorry.
And... thank you very much.
But you've done enough.
Because those are my thoughts, my feelings, and my memories.
I will carry them myself.
They are things that I should not have lost.
I beg you, may I...
May I please have my weight back?
May I please have my mother back?
It seems that when Senjougahara's mother got immersed in the cult,
Senjougahara was a fifth grader.
She had a serious illness at that time.
Because of her daughter's illness, Senjougahara's mother wanted to seek spiritual assurance.
Then...
...Senjougahara managed to survive a major surgical operation.
But her mother became increasingly immersed in the cult.
After that, the relationship between Senjougahara and her mother became strained.
It seems that she stopped talking to her mother during her middle school years.
And then...
Just before graduation from middle school, an incident occurred.
This resulted in...
...the breaking up of the family.
It became irreparable.
It was then that Senjougahara met a crab.
A weight crab... That sort of thing, Araragi-kun...
is also called an emotion god.
Also, a bond is formed through a combination of feelings and protection.
That is to say, when Senjougahara met the crab,
she cut all ties to her mother so she could stop feeling troubled regarding such matters.
She stopped thinking about those feelings, and therefore lost weight.
She chose to cheat herself.
It actually isn't such a bad thing.
This case especially, since even if she gets her feelings back,
her mother won't come back and the family will remain broken.
Even then, even so...
Because of that, Senjougahara Hitagi wanted to take them back.
She begged to get them back.
Those unbearable feelings of her mother, memories, and frustrations.
Like what Oshino said, maybe nothing will change.
It's not like nothing can be changed.
Besides, it isn't a futile effort.
At least I gained an important friend.
Who are you referring to?
You.
Thank you, Araragi-kun.
I'm really grateful to you.
I apologize for all my actions up till now.
Even though saying such a thing now is shameless, if we can get along from now on...
I'll be very happy.
All right brother, it's morning now!
It's about time you woke up.
I just went to sleep...
Oh, you were out all night, again?
Seriously.
You're the only person who hasn't had breakfast yet, brother.
That's right, bro—
But still, my body feels heavy.
Do I have a fever or something?
I might as well mention it.
My weight is 55 Kg.
But...
Hey, hey.
I see.
Gods really are careless creatures.
I'm Karen.
I'm Tsukihi.
When you say jungle-gyms nowadays...
I've said it before!
Maybe you've said too much.
Too much?
What do you mean by "jungle"?
It's not a jungle.
What about gym?
It's not a gym either.
That's false advertisement!
Then can they name it so you can be happy?
Maybe something like "Despair Special"?
That's seriously sounds pretty bad!
Then once again, let's start the preview riddle.
Riddle.
You're a bus driver.
I can't believe I'm the bus driver!
The three of us rode it in the first episode!
Yep, we rode it!
What is the name of the person who drives your bus?
Don't go too fast!
Next episode: Mayoi Snail Part 1.
All right, the answer is your name.
You made it like a magic show.